A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices, New Delhi, India, RG 6, SG 7 FA396
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Indian Agricultural Program - General Administrative Files, ca. 1952-1976; I1; 21 __Boxes __6.6 cubic feet
  - Operating Records - Personnel Policy Files - Delhi Medical and Nursing Home Benefits Scheme, 1959-1964 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Operating Records - Personnel Policy Files - Delhi Medical and Nursing Home Benefits Scheme, 1959-1964 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Operating Records - Personnel Policy Files - Health Care Program, 1960-1973 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Operating Records - Personnel Policy Files - Health Care Program, 1960-1973 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Operating Records - Personnel Policy Files - Leave Policy, 1958-1968 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Operating Records - Personnel Policy Files - Perquisites, 1959-1973 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Operating Records - Personnel Policy Files - Retirement Security Fund, 1953-1972 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Operating Records - Personnel Policy Files - Retirement Security Fund, 1953-1972 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Operating Records - Record-Keeping and Filing Procedures, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory - General, 1957-1972 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - Manuscript, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - 5 x 7 Cards, 1957-1974 (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - 5 x 7 Cards, 1957-1974 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - 5 x 7 Cards, 1957-1974 (Box 14, Folder 85)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - 5 x 7 Cards, 1957-1974 (Box 15, Folder 86)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - 5 x 7 Cards, 1957-1974 (Box 16, Folder 87)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - 5 x 7 Cards, 1957-1974 (Box 17, Folder 88)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - 5 x 7 Cards, 1957-1974 (Box 18, Folder 89)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Inventory of Field Equipment - 5 x 7 Cards, 1957-1974 (Box 19, Folder 90)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Lists of Equipment Supplied, 1957-1972 (Box 20, Folder 91)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Lists of Equipment Supplied, 1957-1972 (Box 20, Folder 92)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Lists of Equipment Supplied, 1957-1972 (Box 20, Folder 93)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Lists of Equipment Supplied, 1957-1972 (Box 20, Folder 94)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Lists of Equipment Supplied, 1957-1972 (Box 20, Folder 95)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Lists of Equipment Supplied, 1957-1972 (Box 20, Folder 96)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Lists of Equipment Supplied, 1957-1972 (Box 20, Folder 97)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Master List of Equipment Supplied, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 98)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Master List of Equipment Supplied, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 99)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Master List of Equipment Supplied, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 100)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Master List of Equipment Supplied, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 101)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Receipts - Equipment Sales, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 102)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Transfer of Title, Donation of Equipment, 1970-1973 (Box 21, Folder 103)
  - Operating Records - Supplies and Equipment - Transfer of Title, Donation of Equipment, 1970-1973 (Box 21, Folder 104)
- Indian Agricultural Program - Administrative Files, 1950-1975, n.d.; I2; 12 __Boxes __4.8 cubic feet
  Subgroup I, Series 2, IAP Administrative Files, includes correspondence, minutes, program development files, and fellowship and scholarship files (1950-1975) relating to the planning and review of the IAP research programs and to international programs with which the Foundation collaborated.
  Field office correspondence with New York headquarters, the Indian Council of Agricultural Research (ICAR), and the Ministry of Food and Agricultural fills boxes 22 through 25. Correspondence with the New York office relates to travel, staffing needs, funding, equipment and supplies, and seed shipments. Letters between IAP field directors and the Directors General of the ICAR, Dr. B. P. Pal and Dr. A. B. Joshi, pertain to meetings and workshops, crop programs, research evaluations and publications.
  Correspondence with representatives of international organizations and agencies is arranged alphabetically by country or name of organization and fills boxes 29 through 33. Letters concern agriculture assistance programs undertaken by other organizations, as well as preparations for IAP staff visits to countries outside India. As a whole, the correspondence reveals the international network of technical know-how brought to bear upon improving Asian agriculture between 1958 and 1973.
  The program development files in Series 2 contain influential reports on RF agricultural policy and Indian agriculture. These include a statement by RF Director Warren Weaver, "The Program in the Natural Sciences," prepared in 1950, one year before the creation of the Natural Sciences and Agriculture Division. Also present is a 1951 memorandum from Weaver to Dr. Richmond K. Anderson, the RF Representative in India, in which Weaver outlines procedures for referring to New York Indian requests for information on agricultural grants. Also of interest is the 1952 report, "Notes on Indian Agriculture," by J. G. Harrar, Paul C. Mangelsdorf, and Warren Weaver. This report led to several follow-up visits by RF representatives and ultimately to India's request for a collaborative agricultural program.
  Records are arranged alphabetically by type of material from "Correspondence" through "Program development files." These files are followed by International Development Programs, International Organizations, and United States Agencies.
  Correspondence with representatives of international organizations and agencies is arranged alphabetically by country or name of organization.
  Additional material on international collaboration is contained in Series 4, Crop Improvement Programs, and Series 6, Agricultural Research Institutes. Series 4 includes information on the Inter-Asian Corn Improvement Program (1963-1973), other international maize assistance programs (1961-1971), and the IRRI (International Rice Research Institute) (1967-1973). Correspondence relating to CIMMYT (Centro International de Mejoramiento de Maiz y Trigo) and its cooperation with the All India Maize and Wheat programs is contained in Series 6, Subseries 3.
  Additional reports on Indian agriculture are located in Record Group 1.1 (Projects), Series 464 (India).
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 105)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 106)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 107)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 108)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 109)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 110)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 111)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 112)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1956-1969 (Box 22, Folder 113)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 114)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 115)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 116)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 117)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 118)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 119)
  - Correspondence - Administration and Organization, 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 120)
  - Correspondence - Baird, Guy B., 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 0120a)
  - Correspondence - Conferences and Meetings, 1957-1959, 1961-1966 (Box 23, Folder 121)
  - Correspondence - Conferences and Meetings, 1957-1959, 1961-1966 (Box 23, Folder 122)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Director General, Indian Council of Agricultural Research (ICAR), 1965-1968 (Box 23, Folder 123)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 124)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 125)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 126)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 127)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 128)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 129)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 130)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR, 1967-1973 (Box 24, Folder 131)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Ministry of Food and Agriculture/ICAR - Research Evaluations, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 132)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - National Commission on Agriculture, 1970-1973 (Box 25, Folder 133)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - National Scientific Committee on Plant Introduction and Quarantine, 1968-1971 (Box 25, Folder 134)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - National Scientific Committee on Plant Introduction and Quarantine, 1968-1971 (Box 25, Folder 135)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - National Scientific Committee on Plant Introduction and Quarantine, 1968-1971 (Box 25, Folder 136)
  - Correspondence - Government of India - Planning Commission, 1971-1973 (Box 25, Folder 137)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1961-1973 (Box 25, Folder 138)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Policy, 1957-1967 (Box 25, Folder 139)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Policy, 1957-1967 (Box 25, Folder 140)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Policy, 1957-1967 (Box 25, Folder 141)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Policy, 1968-1973 (Box 26, Folder 142)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Tax on Stipends, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 143)
  - Fellowships and Travel Grants - Policy, 1965-1975 (Box 26, Folder 144)
  - Minutes - Staff Meetings, 1958, 1967-1972 (Box 26, Folder 145)
  - Minutes - Staff Meetings, 1958, 1967-1972 (Box 26, Folder 146)
  - Program Development Files - Establishment of RF Joint Office (Medical-Natural Sciences/Agricultural Sciences), 1950-1958 (Box 26, Folder 147)
  - Program Development Files - IAP Project Papers, 1967-1971 (Box 26, Folder 148)
  - Program Development Files - IAP Project Papers, 1967-1971 (Box 26, Folder 149)
  - Program Development Files - IAP Program Planning, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 150)
  - Program Development Files - IAP Program Planning, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 151)
  - Program Development Files - IAP Program Planning, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 152)
  - Program Development Files - IAP Program Review, 1969-1970, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 153)
  - Program Development Files - IAP Program Review, 1969-1970, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 154)
  - Program Development Files - Library Program, 1958-1967 (Box 27, Folder 155)
  - Program Development Files - Library Program, 1958-1967 (Box 27, Folder 156)
  - Program Development Files - Library Program, 1958-1967 (Box 27, Folder 157)
  - Program Development Files - Library Program, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 158)
  - Program Development Files - Library Program, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 159)
  - Program Development Files - Library Program - File of Consultant Dr. George S. Bonn, 1967-1971 (Box 28, Folder 160)
  - Program Development Files - Libraries, Various - Haryana Agricultural University Library, 1970, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 161)
  - Program Development Files - Libraries, Various - Indian Agricultural Research Institute Library, 1959-1960, 1969-1970, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 162)
  - Program Development Files - Libraries, Various - Indian Agricultural Research Institute Library, 1959-1960, 1969-1970, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 163)
  - Program Development Files - Libraries, Various - Indian Council of Agricultural Research (ICAR) Library, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 164)
  - Program Development Files - Libraries, Various - Indian Veterinary Research Institute Library, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 165)
  - Program Development Files - Libraries, Various - Uttar Pradesh Agricultural University Library, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 166)
  - International Development Programs - Afghnistan, 1969-1972 (Box 29, Folder 167)
  - International Development Programs - Africa, 1968-1973 (Box 29, Folder 168)
  - International Development Programs - Africa, 1968-1973 (Box 29, Folder 169)
  - International Development Programs - Indonesia, 1968-1973 (Box 29, Folder 170)
  - International Development Programs - Japan, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 171)
  - International Development Programs - Nepal, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 172)
  - International Development Programs - Nepal, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 173)
  - International Development Programs - Nepal, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 174)
  - International Development Programs - Pakistan, 1966-1972 (Box 29, Folder 175)
  - International Development Programs - Sri Lanka, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 176)
  - International Development Programs - Taiwan, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 177)
  - International Development Programs - Thailand, 1965-1973 (Box 30, Folder 178)
  - International Development Programs - Turkey, 1967, 1969-1972, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 179)
  - International Development Programs - Turkey, 1967, 1969-1972, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 180)
  - International Organizations - Agricultural Development Council, 1960-1968, 1970-1973 (Box 31, Folder 181)
  - International Organizations - Agricultural Development Council, 1960-1968, 1970-1973 (Box 31, Folder 182)
  - International Organizations - Arid Lands Agricultural Development Council, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 183)
  - International Organizations - Asia Foundation, 1966-1967 (Box 31, Folder 184)
  - International Organizations - Canadian Agricultural Task Force, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 185)
  - International Organizations - Danforth Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 31, Folder 186)
  - International Organizations - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1958-1972 (Box 31, Folder 187)
  - International Organizations - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1958-1972 (Box 31, Folder 188)
  - International Organizations - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1958-1972 (Box 31, Folder 189)
  - International Organizations - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1958-1972 (Box 31, Folder 190)
  - International Organizations - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1958-1972 (Box 31, Folder 191)
  - International Organizations - Ford Foundation, 1958-1966 (Box 31, Folder 192)
  - International Organizations - Ford Foundation, 1958-1966 (Box 31, Folder 193)
  - International Organizations - Ford Foundation, 1967-1973 (Box 32, Folder 194)
  - International Organizations - Ford Foundation, 1967-1973 (Box 32, Folder 195)
  - International Organizations - Ford Foundation, 1967-1973 (Box 32, Folder 196)
  - International Organizations - Ford Foundation, 1967-1973 (Box 32, Folder 197)
  - International Organizations - International Basic Economy Corporation, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 198)
  - International Organizations - International Development Research Center, 1970-1973 (Box 32, Folder 199)
  - International Organizations - International Flavors and Fragrances, 1969-1970 (Box 32, Folder 200)
  - International Organizations - International Monetary Fund, 1958 (Box 32, Folder 201)
  - International Organizations - International Society of Soil Science, 1959-1960 (Box 32, Folder 202)
  - International Organizations - United National Development Program, 1968-1973 (Box 32, Folder 203)
  - United States Agencies - American Peace Corps, 1966-1971 (Box 32, Folder 204)
  - United States Agencies - Embassy of the United States of America, 1968-1972 (Box 33, Folder 205)
  - United States Agencies - Embassy of the United States of America - Education Committee, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 206)
  - United States Agencies - United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1968-1973 (Box 33, Folder 207)
  - United States Agencies - United States Agency for International Development (USAID), 1968-1973 (Box 33, Folder 208)
  - United States Agencies - United States Agency for International Development (USAID) - Adaptive Research Programs, 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 209)
  - United States Agencies - United States Agency for International Development (USAID) - Asian Seminar on Agricultural Universities, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 210)
  - United States Agencies - United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), 1959-1972 (Box 33, Folder 211)
  - United States Agencies - United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), 1959-1972 (Box 33, Folder 212)
  - United States Agencies - United States Educational Foundation in India, 1968-1973 (Box 33, Folder 213)
  - United States Agencies - United States-India Women's College Exchange Program, 1963-1966 (Box 33, Folder 214)
  - United States Agencies - United States-India Women's College Exchange Program, 1963-1966 (Box 33, Folder 215)
- Indian Agricultural Program - Officers' Diaries, 1957-1975; I3; 5 __Boxes __1.8 cubic feet
  Series 3 contains the daily office diaries of IAP Field Directors Ralph W. Cummings (1957-1966), Guy B. Baird (1959-1971), Ordway Starnes (1971-1973), and RF Representative Wayne H. Freeman (1974-1975). These diaries provide a nearly unbroken account of the writers' administrative and scientific activities, constituting a unique source of information and commentary. Diary entries were generally hand-written and then typed by an assistant. The field office retained a copy, and the original type-written copy was sent to New York with one or two carbon copies for filing in other office correspondence. Thus, excerpts of these diaries appear in Record Group 1.1 (Projects) and 1.2 (Projects) and occasionally in Record Group 2 (General Correspondence).
  Alphabetically arranged by author.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Officers' diaries are open for scholarly research provided that (1) the diarist is deceased and (2) the volume to be examined is at least twenty years old. All reasonable efforts will be made to determine the fate of the diarist(s), but if such efforts are fruitless then the material will remain closed to scholarly research until 100 years after the officer's year of birth.
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 216)
    Restricted - RF Officer Diaries.
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 217)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 218)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 219)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 220)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 221)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 222)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 223)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 224)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 225)
  - Baird, Guy B., November 1959-May 1968 (Box 34, Folder 226)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 227)
    General note
    (copy 2)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 228)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 229)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 230)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 231)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 232)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 233)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 234)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 235)
  - Baird, Guy B., December 1959-December 1968 (Box 35, Folder 236)
  - Baird, Guy B., January 1969-December 1970 (Box 36, Folder 237)
  - Baird, Guy B., January 1969-December 1971 (Box 36, Folder 238)
    (copy 3)
  - Baird, Guy B., January 1969-December 1971 (Box 36, Folder 239)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., April-August 1957 (Box 36, Folder 240)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., January-June 1958 (Box 36, Folder 241)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., August 1958-November 1959 (Box 36, Folder 242)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., August 1958-November 1959 (Box 36, Folder 243)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., December 1959-April 1960 (Box 37, Folder 244)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., September 1960-November 1961 (Box 37, Folder 245)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., September 1960-November 1961 (Box 37, Folder 246)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., February-April 1962 (Box 37, Folder 247)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., October 1962 (Box 37, Folder 248)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., June, July, December 1963 (Box 37, Folder 249)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., January-June 1964 (Box 37, Folder 250)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., January-June 1964 (Box 37, Folder 251)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., January-June 1964 (Box 37, Folder 252)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., September-December 1964, June-July 1965 (Box 37, Folder 253)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., November 1965-May 1966 (Box 37, Folder 254)
  - Cummings, Ralph W., June-August 1966 (Box 38, Folder 255)
  - Freeman, Wayne H., February 1974-October 1975 (Box 38, Folder 256)
  - Starnes, Ordway, December 1971-November 1973 (Box 38, Folder 257)
- Indian Agricultural Program - Crop Improvement Programs, 1955-1973, n.d.; I4; 57 __Boxes __21.4 cubic feet
  Series 4, Crop Improvement Programs, is the largest of the series in Subgroup I (boxes 39 to 94) and contains the records of the All India Coordinated Crop Improvement programs, the seed development program, and miscellaneous food study programs.
  Certain types of records are common to Subseries 1 through 6. Correspondence relating to the establishment and organization of the particular program appears first within each subseries. Substantial correspondence exists for maize (1957-72), millet (1965-68, 1970-71), rice (1964-83), sorghum (1957-73), wheat (1965-73), and seed development (1959-73). Correspondence of a miscellaneous character follows, treating such technical matters as experiment station operations, equipment maintenance, conference and workshop scheduling, training programs, relations with other agricultural organizations, and research programs in seed collection, breeding, entomology and pathology.
  Correspondence is typically followed by unpublished and published reports summarizing the results of experimental tests. These reports are arranged alphabetically by corporate author in Subseries 1, Maize, and alphabetically by title throughout the rest of the series. Filed with unpublished reports are manuscript drafts of reports on various aspects of the research programs. Also present are "trip reports" written by staff from the field.